Kiran Kumar Budde Phone#: 469-885-7674

Email ID: krnvarma6@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/kiranbudde

GitHub: https://github.com/krnbudde

DevOps/Site Reliability Engineer/AWS Cloud Engineer with more than six years of experience in Development, Automation, Support, SME, and Designing and building Continuous Integration and Continuous Deployment pipelines and frameworks. He has experience using tools, languages, and technologies such as Python, Scala, SQL, Shell Script, Docker, Snowflake, Git, Jenkins, SonarQube, Ansible, Spark, and Hadoop. He is also well versed in Cloud Infrastructure like AWS Services such as Elastic Map Reduce (EMR) and EC2, S3, SNS, SQS, ECS, Lambda, etc., and has been exposed to Azure and GCP cloud technologies using SDLC policies.

TECHNOLOGIES:	
Programming and Scripting Languages	Python, Scala, Java, SQL, SnowSQL, Shell
Databases	Snowflake, PostgreSQL, MySQL
Containerized/Virtualization	Docker, AWS ECS, VMware
Cloud Services	AWS EMR, EC2, Lambda, ECS, S3, Route53, Load Balancer, SNS, SQS, EFS, RDS, Cloud Formation, Security Groups, GCP Cloud Compute engines, IAM, Cloud Storage and Azure VM
CI/CD Tools	Jenkins, SonarQube, Ansible, Puppet
Version control	Git, Bit Bucket
Monitoring	PagerDuty, Splunk
ITIL and Other	ServiceNow, Jira, HPQC, Spark, Hadoop, JFrog, Nexus
Web Services	Nginx, Gunicorn, WSGI, Unicorn, Fast Api, Flask, Apache Tomcat

CERTIFICATION:

- AWS Certified DevOps Professional
- AWS Certified Developer Associate

EDUCATION:

- MS, Computer Science, Silicon Valley University
- Bachelor of Technology, Information Technology, JNTUH University, Hyderabad, India

EXPERIENCE:

Consulting Firm On assignment at EQUIFAX (REMOTE), Dallas, TX DEVOPS/SRE ENGINEER

- Experience in working with Terraform and AWS
- Worked with Jenkins and CICD pipelines
- Strong knowledge in debugging and automation using Shell/PowerShell, Python

JUL 2024 - Present

- Strong knowledge in CICD and SDLC along with an understanding of Jira methodologies
- Worked with tools such as HashiCorp Vault, GCP, and Kubernetes
- Migrated infra from legacy to AWS cloud using Jenkins CICD and Terraform
- Experience in debugging application issues and infra issues for both Linux and Windows environments Experience in Windows patch management and Fixing vulnerabilities
- Responsible for installing and maintaining Security and Vulnerability tools such as Qualys and Sentinel One and Resolving CVE vulnerable issues
- Created automation to create/update/move Vault secrets
- Created automation to fix day-to-day issues observed during migrations
- Created automation for 60 days of Image rotation to keep AMI and images in the Latest and Vulnerability free

Consulting Firm MAY 2024 - JUL 2024

On assignment at WALMART(REMOTE), Dallas, TX

DEVOPS ENGINEER

- Strong knowledge of Python, Jenkins, Terraform vault, and CICD tools services
- Created Jenkins pipelines using languages such as Python, bash shell scripting, and PowerShell
- Knowledge of Kubernetes, node deployments, and tools such as Kubectl to maintain and configure pods and services within the Kubernetes platform
- Worked with Jira services and created documentation pages such as confluence pages
- Worked with SDLC methodologies in a day-to-day work environment
- Team interactions and building strong relations with the DEV and SRE teams and working together to support and maintain the critical applications
- Responsible for deploying and managing Kubernetes clusters in production environments
- Used Kubernetes primitives like pods, services, deployments, and stateful sets
- Experience in automating Kubernetes operations with tools like Helm and Ansible
- Experience with troubleshooting Kubernetes-related issues and optimizing cluster performance

Consulting Firm SEP 2018 – MAR 2024

On assignment at CAPITAL ONE, PLANO, TX

DEVOPS ENGINEER

- Maintained application and infrastructure by staying on-call rotations and debugging issues for production issues
- Developed streamlined frameworks for Data processing and maintained application support and production support
- Involved and worked in Production deployment every week for critical applications
- Developed application and infrastructure design and architecture for running more reliable and cost-efficient
- Provided extensive support and solutions to the product users on questions related to the Product and helped them achieve their business needs from the product
- Provided extensive support and solutions to the data analysts and data engineers on questions related to the framework and helped them achieve their business needs from the framework
- Provided solutions to the business teams on developing metrics much more efficiently and meet their business needs
- Developed applications using REST API's for data pipelines for easy executions and data movements
- Developed frameworks with API hosting services like Flask, Fast API and Uviron
- Developed a high availability framework using Nginx, Gunicorn and WSGI on top of Flask using Python
- Used Terraform to map more complex dependencies and identify network issues
- Developed SQL scripts for business logics in Snowflake databases
- Developed Data pipelines for build, test, and deployment process
- Built Data pipelines to transform the data and store them in the database like Snowflake
- Created and maintained Docker Images for ECS Cluster and worked on creating Service and Task Definitions

- Worked on developing the CloudFormation templates to use spot instances for EC2, EMR, ECS by following the High Availability and achieved the reduction of cost
- Built an Internal tool using Python to use the EMR cluster for big data applications in an efficient and optimized way
- Migrated the application frameworks to microservices and containerized using docker and deployed as services with the auto-scaling as high availability applications
- Built robust systems with an eye on the long-term maintenance and support of the application
- Worked with Amazon web services such as EC2, EMR, ECS, S3, SNS, SQS and Lambda etc. for Data pipeline
 applications
- Developed pipelines to build, test, and deploy in UNIX environments
- Worked on support activities and helped customers get the issues resolved before they reached the SLA's
- Worked closely with the Architecture teams to build a reliable and secure environment for data teams to develop their metrics in a guided process

TECHNOLOGY SPA, DALLAS, TX DEVOPS ENGINEER

MAY 2018 - AUG 2018

- Worked with Docker EE using Swarm, deployed the applications as a stack into the nodes running in Azure
- Worked with a Logging application named "Logz.io" which was SaaS-based ELK stack and offered a solution to deploy into their production environment
- Worked with FluentD to configure, filter, and ship their logs from docker daemon, containers, and nodes to logz.io using an API Token and Logz.io container along with a fluent container running as a single stack
- Worked with the team in creating config files for FluentD in assigning and using rightful filters to obtain their goal in using the application
- Worked with monitoring tools such as Prometheus, Grafana, and Alert Manager and deployed these
 applications in docker swarm and created visual dashboards in Grafana to visualize the data obtained from
 Prometheus
- Used Alert Manager to configure the notification channel to trigger alerts and created the alert rules to notify the channel whenever the specified threshold exceeds and recovers
- Created different kinds of dashboards in Grafana to visualize Memory usage, I/O
 usage to and from the network, CPU usage, Disk usage, Swap memory usage, and so on in host level, node
 level, and swarm level
- Developed Docker Images using tools like Docker Compose, Kubernetes, for Orchestrating and deploying the services related to the Containers and with container-based deployments using Docker, working with Docker images, Docker hub
- Implemented the branching, tagging, developing, manage Pre-commit, and post-commit hook scripts and maintaining the versions across different Source Code Management (SCM) tools like Git, Subversion (SVN) on Linux and Windows platforms and SCM client tools like GitLab, GitHub, GitGUI, and Bitbucket
- Worked on AWS CloudWatch to monitor the performance environment instances for operational and performance metrics during load testing
- Experienced in designing a Terraform and deploying it in cloud deployment manager to spin up resources like cloud virtual networks, Compute Engines in public and private subnets along with Auto Scaler in Google Cloud platform
- Developed the CloudFormation to create EMR, EC2, Lambda and other variety of resources
- Implemented the Blue-green deployments with Route 53 and Elastic Load Balancer to have high-availability and Regional Isolation
- Responsible for creating and managing users and groups, installation of packages and services on Red Hat Enterprise Linux
- Implemented the Prometheus Integration on all EC2 instances and created dashboards to monitor Infrastructure and Container Metrics.